it's been a couple of weeks since my
last full proper hermitcraft episode did
you miss me and my oh my has it been
good to take a break it is extremely
healthy to take a break and a step back
as YouTubers don't normally get
traditional holidays it's basically up
to us when we take a holiday and I
really feel like I needed one so so
we're back on the hermitcraft server
after quite a long time now I haven't
been doing nothing you might notice that
there's a particularly ugly random
staircase up to the door that never
opens the interior of the Mansion but
before we get into that there's a few
things that I need to talk about one is
my base what are we going to be doing
for the rest of the season we don't know
how long it's going to go on for but
we've got at least a few months and the
Mansion despite all its glory is not
where I would like it to be I have been
firmly ignoring this giant ugly hole
that I made myself I literally dug
myself into a hole but I want to commit
myself in the next few episodes to
tackle this monstrosity that is the
interior of the base and taking a bit of
time off I was able to kind of realize
what I want to do in here it is quite a
big space but maybe not as big as you
might expect it certainly looks smaller
on the inside than it does on the
outside now I have actually decided what
I want to make in here and I do need to
kind of start off by creating a floor
now basically I'm going to fill this
with a bunch of micro Farms meaning some
sheep
some more melons and pumpkin farms
basically a little bit of everything
maybe even some iron Farms I want to
move my villager breeder in here and
expand my trading Hall which is why I
have this because these two Villages
over here it what I don't know what's
wrong with this to be honest with you
because I've given these guys so much
grain and it's never enough yeah these
guys have been here since the start of
the uh the season so I think it's
probably a good idea that we we move
them the moving Villages is a pain in
the butt so we're gonna I think actually
despite me sort of preparing this
there's a there's a lot man you know
it's been two weeks there's a lot of
I've got a lot of ideas and I'm
struggling to get them out so I am going
to be working on the interior of this
but this is more of my long-term project
so we'll revisit this later in the
episode because behind the Mansion you
might remember one of the wages from the
turf war was that scar
was going to help me with the back of
the Mansion now I also happened to take
away his little baby boy here grogu
little baby Yoda adorable now
you guys know me I'm a little bit like a
cat chasing its own tail I don't know
what to do with it once I've got it so I
kind of I'm just gonna give it back I'm
gonna give it back to scar so so what
I've got here is I've got a lodestone
compass that is you know directly
attached to this lodestone here and it
says this thank you for being an amazing
friend wholesome I know please take baby
Yoda back and a present from me now
about that wager basically I want I want
to get scar to come here and take a look
at what we have to work on it is uh yeah
it's gonna be a big project and I I'm
very excited to get Scar's help because
you know Scar and I have been on kind of
opposite sides of the of things for the
the last few months and it's good I've
made him a little present box
essentially I know that he loves smooth
quartz and I gave him some diamonds and
some golden carrots it's basically a
thank you for being an amazing friend
box and then returning the tail now that
I got it
so let's go over to the barge real quick
because I haven't checked up on the shop
at all in like two or three weeks uh you
may think you have some idea of what
you're in possession is but you do not
soon he will be back with me and he
means more oh no this is a Mandalorian
thing skull don't worry scar you can
have him back actually in fact I'm gonna
before this gets out of hand or
escalates there you are lodestone
Compass back to baby Yoda it's taken me
quite it's taken me like five minutes
just to catch up with everyone
I'm running so fast I feel like I'm
running so fast why does it feel like
I'm running so fast oh my goodness I
completely missed the Christmas tree
that's right I was told that there's
presents under here
is there one of this must be mine this
must be literally the last one left yeah
thank you scar this is a gift from the
mayor to everyone oh that's not you know
what I really need shulker boxes so this
is really good thank you very much scar
right let's take a look and catch up on
what's going on in the barge not a huge
not a lot of sales but then that's not
exactly surprising
oh goodness what is this
there's a bunch of glass in the middle
of the barge that I I didn't I have
nothing to do with this
hold on does this say it's definitely
spell something out
uh
uh oh
you take two weeks away from YouTube and
you forget how to read
I cannot read this I can't read glass I
can't make out with this okay that's
okay
that's not a letter
that is not a letter k
that's not a letter KL
e
g l
o s s
clay gloss what is this
am I going insane can anybody read this
I I know I'm not like the best at
English but what's clear gloss am I I'm
missing something here hopefully I don't
have to feel too bad about taking this
down because I can't read it I mean
that's not a letter this is what two
weeks away from the internet does to you
you just you just forget everything
apparently how to English hey we sold
some Rockets
we got one sale normally the barge is
way better that does way better than
this oh wait wait wait
congrats on your free glass oh
clear gloss
more like free glass
oh this is what did I do to deserve this
I didn't sign up to Shady ease
no
no no no
no bad
please tell me they haven't done this to
all of mine
no
[Music]
oh please okay it doesn't seem to be no
there's how
nice oh my goodness okay we have we have
made some sales and I don't know what I
did to deserve this glass but
I think I need to put in a formal
complaint at Shady ease but I I'm also
kind of scared what happens to people
that complain about Shady ease I never
signed up but maybe see look here's how
I think this might play out I'm not cool
with the free glass thing I didn't sign
up for this right okay so my thought is
oh let's complain like a formal
complaint to Shady ease but what what if
I complain and they compensate me with
free glass I don't what do I do
I think I've been I've been trapped up
and I'm Vanishing out I'm vanished I'm
out too much free glass and I'm gone no
I'm gonna do it I'm submitting a formal
complaint to head office
how have I never been in here
B-Dubs I didn't know B-Dubs was part of
shady ease sign up a friend did someone
sign me up not happy with a subscription
impossible but just in case unsubscribe
by replacing your paper with a diamond
block
did someone sign me up oh no I'm good
I'm gonna get I'm you know I I justify
this
formal complaint I did not sign up for
this please take back free glass or
gloss I'm not sure anymore gee
oh this has so much potential to
backfire you know what this free glass
actually probably won't go amiss it's
exactly the right color yeah I I
probably will I mean it's not a bad
thing I'll just keep this for later okay
so update is the barge has made a few
diamonds I've found a few more lying
around so we're not doing too badly and
the stock isn't too bad so we can leave
this well alone for the time being oh
it's so funny that Scar's given me a
bunch of smooth quartz because that's
exactly what I've gifted him
we may have just traded stuff okay so
what now so I have been thinking and
I've got several ideas for the next few
episodes like like I said too many to
even discuss I can't get all my thoughts
out but there is something very
important that I want to kind of kick
off in today's episode as a big return
now you see on hermitcraft there there
are some not really there are no real
rules but we do have gentleman rules
okay so I mean an easy example of that
is you know when you go to the shopping
district you pay for what it is you
don't you don't just take I just found
some oh man I'm finding this glass
everywhere
oh this is a nightmare but anyway when
you go to shopping district you pay for
your goods you know you don't under
charge and you don't steal I mean it's
it's simple right gentleman's rules
however what's really interesting is
over the time that I've been on
hermitcraft the viewers you guys have
actually made up your own rules I don't
know where they've come from but like
for some reason the viewers think some
things are rules within the hermitcraft
server
and it's just not true and I today in
today's episode I'm going to prove that
point so I feel that the some of the
viewers think that it's a rule that
you're not allowed to touch anyone
else's base
right that you're not allowed to just
turn up and build in someone else's base
or mess with it or whatever it might be
it's just not true and I'm gonna prove
it and it's gonna be super fun and we're
gonna see how far we can push this so I
have renamed this box secret base box
and I have got a bunch of blocks
that are what I'm I've you know I've
clearly spent quite a long time
preparing these I've thought about this
long and hard and what we're gonna do is
we're gonna build a new base a secret
base inside one of our friends bases and
we shall see how long we can keep it a
secret now I've already done some Recon
on this and I've decided that our best
bet is actually impulse's base I've done
some Recon so I thought ethos bass you
guys remember the ethos bass You Can't
Hide a secret base because his whole
base doesn't even have an outside and
then scars base well here's what I'm
thinking right and make a secret base in
here it's impulse online impulse is
online okay this might be a terrible
time to do this but I'm also thinking
right long-term plan I've clearly been
plotting and scheming for the two weeks
that I've been taking a little break but
check it out I've got a little plot here
remember Green Spot I still get to keep
this and I'm thinking C secret base
there I can link it up to my secret base
here secret base there secret base there
secret base there hermitcraft viewers we
are about to embark on a bit of a
journey and I'm not sure how this is
gonna go but after my reconnaissance I
can tell you that this is probably
the best bet now how risky do we make
this well first of all let's do impulse
check impulse is literally right there
okay well I prepare for this oh I'm
rocket please tell me didn't hear the
rocket no I'm good I'm good I'm good
okay right I prepared for this
eventuality to get rid of my username I
have got myself eight minute
invisibility potions so if he looks up
he is only gonna see a floating set of
armor am I Really Gonna do this while
he's right there this is so risky this
is unbelievably risky so I need to make
sure that I've got all the blocks that
match his base so I needed to pick up
some light blue concrete I think I've
got everything else so I've spotted a
way of doing this now my username I
should be able to sneak in pretty easily
now I just need to make no noise now he
is directly below me and he is busy he
looks quite busy so I'm gonna make sure
that my secret base is at the back oh
right here could be really good
all right let's do this time is of the
essence
if we're caught the rule is we start all
over again so here we go right we're
going to start small we can't do we
can't make this two but there's no point
going too big especially if he's right
there time is is of the essence and we
need to make sure that we get ourselves
secured in straight away so I'm
basically gonna just replicate what we
see here so that he doesn't suspect a
thing and I should be able to build here
fairly safely we better do make this
absolutely spot on this is so dangerous
I don't know where he is okay so let's
take a look back you wouldn't notice he
may not notice at all
is he still down there
he's still down there okay good so now
look you'll see that there's a disparity
there
but if I if I replicate this really
quickly on both sides
I think
we will be in the clear
Ness kind of sweating I am kind of
sweating here now will impulse notice
uh he'll definitely notice if I make
mistakes like that why am I doing this
why am I doing this while he's right
there the closer that I'm able to make a
secret base
to like the action you know just through
there the better this is gonna be
okay so I've got two secret rooms here
he might he might just think that he's
made a mistake so now I've got myself a
very modest looking space okay this is
very modest it's a very sort of very
small nook and cranny so here we are now
I mean I can't yeah I can't you can't
see me but that doesn't mean I can't see
you I'm proving the rule wrong here I am
messing with someone's base oh my
goodness green has broken the rules no
this rule doesn't exist you guys made it
up
okay so I brought a bunch of boxes with
me better top up the old invisibility so
as much as I love this futuristic design
I bought a bunch of boxes with me
because I thought I'd mix up the decor a
little bit
and if we get away with these two basic
rooms I I see no reason why we can't
expand and try and push the limits I
must admit building this secret base
will be a lot easier when he's not
online I probably chose the worst time
to do this but I mean if you don't take
a bit of risk when you're building in
your friend's bases what's the point you
know what I mean okay I've only got oh
good oh he's gone he's left
well we weren't discovered and I think
we're safe for a while and while we're
here oh look I'm back while we're here I
think it's worth saying that this
project this very project of building
secret bases inside of my friends bases
to prove a point it doesn't work unless
you guys
are in on it okay so obviously this base
here you guys know where it is and you
know how to get in and all that kind of
stuff well I actually haven't managed to
make a door yet but if you guys go and
tell impulse then The Jig Is up like
this this really only works if all of
you guys keep the secret with me which
would be absolutely amazing although
this that's never gone well that's never
gone well it's it's usually always
spoiled by someone just going straight
to their comments saying korean's made a
secret base in your base and it's ruined
but we'll see we'll see what happens and
if this gets discovered then we'll just
have to make another one and be more
secretive and then I can't trust you
ever again do you want that do you want
me to trust you the next big question is
how do I hide the entrance
I did bring some Redstone with me
but I guess I didn't think this through
very well what am I doing there's a
hidden space right here I've been I've
been over complicating this I didn't
need to do all that
there's just there's just a full-on
hidden space in here
oh man this is just made this is just
made all the difference in the world
there is absolutely no reason for
impulse to come anywhere near this and
there's no way he can see me from the
inside of his own base oh man okay give
me half an hour I'm gonna turn this into
a real hidden base this card this is
this has changed the world
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thing happened while I was doing this
time lapse okay so here's impulse's base
and here is my secret base in here right
now fortunately at the time I'm here
crouching and I have no idea what's
about to happen right now if we go above
we can see the only other hermit online
including impulse Corrales and XP are
why they're here I don't know but if we
play this
oh man I don't know whether I got caught
or not so they go okay they go inside
impulses base and where did they go XP
then finds this wandering Trader okay
and he clearly tells the other guys
maybe Corrales that there's a Wandering
Trader because all of a sudden Corrales
comes as well now at this point I'm
thinking oh no this is over I've been
seen
but they are not suspicious at all from
what I can tell and here's me on the
inside panicking my brains off thinking
I've been found
I'm wondering what on Earth they're
doing
I don't think that I've been found but
they do look very suspicious this is so
unfortunate on so many levels I have no
idea what they're talking about but they
are looking directly at me which is so
weird they even go underwater
and maybe they see a bit of spruce which
is weird but I think
I think I got away with it I think this
villager maybe gave me away or maybe I
got away with it I don't know I may have
been rumbled by this guy here
stupid wondering Trader so that was a
pretty close call and I've been waiting
hours and hours and hours for impulse to
get offline so I can log in safely and I
log in of course he's at he's there he
is right there but he is fortunately
AFK so this hidden base has gone pretty
well and there's I need to kind of give
you a house tour right so I've got my
little hidden entrance over here this is
how you can get in I do have another one
over there right so I've got my super
smelter over here and here's something
really strange that may end up costing
me the secrecy of this base okay so
right behind this pillar here is a
funnel you see probably just saw a
pumpkin shoot up there this was impulses
pumpkin and melon farm but really really
weirdly above here
I can't oh I can't make any noise or I'm
gonna get I'm gonna get found so we're
gonna he's I think he's he's AFK so I
think we're we're safe
so look he has he has all of his Farms
right and it was just going nowhere he
was he I don't know why or what was
going on but basically impulse didn't
connect up his Mel or part of his melon
and pumpkin farm and it was just
Gathering so while I was building this
base
melons and pumpkins were piling up by
the thousands and just despawning so
hilariously I've hijacked his melon and
pumpkin farm and I'm farming them for
him the problem is I can't keep up like
I have been here only a couple of hours
and there's so many melons and pumpkins
that I can't keep up with crafting them
don't worry I'm I'm well to be fair I
think I will use some of these there's
there's just so many but I think it's I
think it's funny how this has played out
that I've managed to build this base in
an area which he kind of messed up
anyway let's continue the tour so this
is the main room this is the main room
here I've got my jukebox with my music
disc oh no he's there was he quick was
he close enough to hear that he's back
that was really silly wasn't it let's
continue this tour so here's the exit
out you can swim out the bottom I've got
my little Wheat Farm here although I
don't know why I bothered making this
when I have unlimited melons and
pumpkins and then over here is my living
room where I've got myself
music just started playing in my base oh
no oh no
oh that was definitely silly
can't type if I type I stand up so what
have I got here I can't really show you
because impulse is right there although
this has been has been a bit of a day
for taking risks so this is my clever
Contraption for checking on impulse
obviously I can't add any Windows to my
secret base so I was wondering how I can
check on what impulse is doing I really
want to check
it's so dangerous he's already Mega
suspicious and I can't I've spent so
long on this secret base now that I I'm
I'm a little bit Keen to keep it and
expand it as far as possible let's take
a look
I can't I can't right click without
revealing myself okay he's down that way
so this is my little this is my
okay so that's that's how that works you
can you can crawl out the little hole in
the wall check what's going on and come
back uh making this bit of redstone was
surprisingly difficult I maybe spent
three hours on it and then ended up
asking Etho anyway
okay right I I can't actually leave
because if I I can't this is such a
major flaw in the design I'm gonna have
to break this if I want to go down while
still crouching well that's the tour of
my secret base it's pretty cozy if you
ask me I kind of went for a a hobbit
hole style thing and funnily enough I
have a brand new melon and pumpkin farm
courtesy of impulse who didn't bother
didn't bother or didn't correctly link
it up to a storage system so I'm kind of
doing him a favor but I need to get out
of here before I'm caught so we're just
gonna swim out of here really fast
really fast
and there we go from the outside you
wouldn't be able to tell
at all and we'll see where this goes in
the future but what can I say
but the secret base game has begun
I really regret playing that jukebox
because I'm not sure I got away with
that very easily okay so I've spent more
time on my secret base than I have my
real base so now let's get cracking on
some interior and we are actually
running out of time for today's episode
so this might this might run over a
little bit but I've got a good idea of
what we want to do and the first thing
is we want to get these villagers
out of here and in
to the interior of the Mansion kind of a
shame that this place is no longer going
to be used but
you know look at it it's uh it looks
really abandoned that's because it kind
of is
all right let's let's release them there
they go bye bye now
whoa
we have ascended
I'm surprised that this has worked
nope nope nope this is how it goes this
is how working with villagers always
goes I've descended all right you get to
go again
again not again
[Laughter]
and he
he's in
sweet that actually went pretty well for
once I need to start making a few plans
in here for next episode I am fully
committed
to fixing the interior this melon and
pumpkin farm has officially I'm
declaring this pathetic after dealing
with the overflowing mess that is
impulses melon and pumpkin farm
this is pathetic I I need more I need
more okay so I'm gonna think about this
off camera ready for next episode
because what we're gonna do well I'm
thinking over here there's gonna be some
sheep and then maybe over here is gonna
be the Villager area maybe and then I I
know I want a big fireplace there's an
awful lot to think about and I'm gonna
think about it I'm gonna plan this ready
for next episode but I have
unfortunately ran out of time because I
was too busy making bases inside of
other people's bases I almost got caught
twice this is gonna be fun please keep
it a secret and I shall see you in the
next episode where hopefully we'll do a
bit of interior work and we'll expand
our secret base as long as we don't get
caught and I have really I I have a
really dastardly way of hiding an
enormous hidden base in impulses bass
but we'll see how that goes if it fails
of course we'll just find somewhere else
to make a base remember
that rule that you can't build in other
people's bases doesn't exist I've just
proven it false it doesn't exist you
guys made it up okay I shall see you in
the next episode good bye